Hal I. Leyshon Papers
Hal I. Leyshon Papers
1948-1965
Leyshon, Hal I.
11.5 linear ft.
American public relations consultant. Collection includes correspondence, press releases, reports, statistics, and other material relating to the American Federation of Musicians and other clients; articles by and about Leyshon, and photographs.
149132
Biographical History
Hal I. Leyshon (1901 or 1902-1966) was an American newspaperman and public relations executive. Leyshon was in the newspaper business for twenty years, eventually becoming editor fo the Miami News (which won a Pulitzer during his tenure). In 1941 he left to open his own public relations firm that specialized in government and labor relations, tourism, travel, aviation, films, media writing and other areas. Among his clients were the American Federation of Musicians, the Democratic National Committee, TWA, the American Red Cross, and the Storer Radio chain.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Hal I. Leyshon Papers contains subject files, writings, printed material and recordings.
General files cover the American Federation of Musicians contract and tours to Florida. Writings contains reports indicating how his company would represent particular firms, monthly activity reports, and news releases relating to clients (the AFM, the Kansas Centennial, and the Florida Development Commission). Printed material consists of books (mostly legislative), magazines, pamphlets, articles, and clippings. Recordings consists of one record album with unspecified content.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically within each series.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Leyshon, Hal I.; American Federation of Musicians.; Public relations consultants -- United States.; Bills (legislative records); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Reports.; Public relations consultants.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Leyshon, 1967.
Inventory
- General files
  - Presidential Advisory Commission on the Arts
    - General (Box 1)
  - American Federation of Musicians
    - Government Subsidies
      - Arts Council Bill, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1963; 4 folders (Box 1)
      - European countries (Box 1)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 1)
      - Information Service and Embassies in U.S. and members of UN (Box 1)
      - Legislation (Box 1)
      - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts (Box 1)
      - National Council on Arts and Government (Box 1)
      - Political platforms, 1960; 1964 (Box 1)
      - Presidential Consultant on the Arts (Box 1)
      - Press releases (Box 2)
      - Proposal for arts observance (Box 2)
      - Publications and reports (Box 2)
      - Resolutions (Box 2)
      - Rockefeller Brothers fund (Box 2)
      - Speech writing / testimony file (Box 2)
      - Twentieth Century Fund (Box 2)
      - Washington Arts Letter (Box 2)
      - Whooping crane (Box 2)
    - Legislation
      - Bulletins (Box 2)
      - Bills introduced (Box 2)
      - Cabaret tax cut (Box 2)
      - Lists, Senate and House (Box 2)
      - Congress brief (Box 2)
      - Congressmen, letters to (Box 2)
      - 10% tax, congressional hearings (Box 2)
      - 20% tax
        - Forand hearings (Box 2)
        - Senate debate, 1958 (Box 2)
        - Background (Box 2)
      - 10% cabaret tax, Internal Revenue Service mailings (Box 2)
      - Mailings (Box 2)
      - Publications, International Musician (Box 2)
      - 50.650
        - Research, International Statistics Bureau (Box 2)
        - Publicity, editorials (Box 3)
        - Publicity, press (Box 3)
        - Publicity press clippings (Box 3)
      - Photographs (Box 3)
      - Publications, press clippings (Box 3)
      - Publicity press (Box 3)
      - Statistics unemployment (Box 3)
      - 20% publications (Box 3)
      - Education
        - Education Act (Box 3)
        - Educational / public television (Box 3)
        - Mutual Cultural Education and Exchange Act (Box 3)
        - Thompson Bill
          - Pledges of support (Box 4)
          - Favorable replies (Box 4)
          - C/c and sympathetic (Box 4)
          - Non-committal (Box 4)
          - Negative replies (Box 4)
          - Replies from AA (Box 4)
          - 1961 and 1964 Roll Call (Box 4)
      - Government subsidies (Box 4)
      - Photographs of 57th annual convention of AFM (Box 4)
  - Florida
    - Administration thank-yous (Box 4)
    - Photographs, February Appreciation Tour (Box 4)
    - Special events
      - Florida Day (Box 4)
      - Appreciation Tour, February (Box 4)
      - Appreciation Tour, April (Box 4)
      - Appreciation Tour, July (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Articles about Leyshon, or Hal Leyshon & Associates (Box 4)
- Writings
  - Reports
    - American National Red Cross, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Andros Utilities Company (Box 5)
    - Central and Southern Florida Flood Control District (Box 5)
    - Hall Brothers (Box 5)
    - Kansas Centennial (Box 5)
    - Lustron House (Box 5)
    - State of New Hampshire (Box 5)
    - Thoroughbred Racing (Box 5)
  - News releases
    - American Federation of Musicians, general (Box 5)
    - American Federation of Musicians, 1948-1955; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Monthly activities reports
    - Florida Development Commission (Box 5)
    - Kansas Centennial, administrative reports, activities (Box 5)
  - Advertising
    - Miscellaneous, 1 folder, 1 volume (Box 5)
- Printed material
  - Books, 105 volumes (Box 6-10)
  - Magazines (Box 10)
  - Pamphlets, 6 volumes (Box 10)
  - Pamphlets (Box 11)
  - Agreements, reports, articles (Box 11)
  - News clippings (Box 11)
  - Newspaper (Oversize 1)
- Recordings
  - Unidentified album (Oversize 1)